Hello guys, welcome to another video of stock
market.  Friends, the
result of this March quarter has been released by ICICI LBAT.
This audited financial result is out.
Quarter and financial year
ended will be covered in today's video.
And along with this,
a final dividend of ₹7 per equity share has also been
recommended by the company.  It has been recommended.  It has
not been declared here.  This means
that the dividend date recommended by the company will be
approved by the company in the next meeting.
So now we will move on to the financial results of the company
and here if we talk about
numbers then the numbers given are
in lakhs.  Look at the gross return this time,
we will cover 100 in the first quarter.
Gross return premium is Rs
693.9 crore.  6474.4 crore in the last quarter.
Lastly, the
gross premium retained is Rs 6263 crore.  Which is seen
increasing quarter on quarter year on year.
After this, the total income that came out here was Rs 5851
crore.  Last quarter it was Rs
582.8 crore and last year it was Rs 5165 crore.
Look, it has been seen going down a lot quarter on quarter
but it is
increasing year on year.
And what is the reason for it being down?
So the income from investment has gone down this time to Rs
625.2 crore, which is
down quarter on quarter.  It
is down year on year also but it is
very less in quarter on quarter.  Due to which the
total income of the company is going down.  The
company's expenses are Rs 5435
crore.  The total expenditure was Rs 5197.4 crore in the last quarter and Rs
463.8 crore in the last.
Expenses are also
increasing quarter on quarter.
Expenses also increased year on year.  There was a
lot of expenditure
quarter on quarter while income was
down.  After which,
if we
see the profit of the company, then the operating profit is Rs. 45.9
crore in the last quarter, Rs. 685.3 crore
in the last year and Rs. 561 crore in the last year,
which is
no doubt seen going down quarter on quarter, year on year,
because see the total income of the company,
quarter on quarter is down and the
expenditure has been very high due to which the
profit is down quarter on quarter,
but year on year the income is increased
but the expenditure has also been very high due to which the
profit is down after tax,
see here the profit of the company which has come out is Rs.
59.5 crore after tax, Rs.
724.4 crore in the last quarter and Rs.
59.5 crore last year.  It is going down quarter on
quarter year on year.
So the company's results have
not been that special.  EPS is ₹1.2 last year and
₹14.5 last year. EPS is ₹1.47.
Quarter on quarter is down.   It has
also gone down year on year.  If
we talk about financial arrangements, the
return premium of Rs
28257.7 crore has been seen
increasing from Rs 25594 crore in 2024.
After which the total income is Rs
22936.6 crore, out of which 24 out of 199 is Rs
1976 crore, which is
seen increasing.  Expenses
increased by ₹669.7 crore to ₹17854 crore in 24.
Expenses have also increased according to income.
Operating profit of Rs 2266.9 crore.  It is coming with an
increase of Rs 195.9 crore in 24.
If we talk about after tax, then the
company's profit after tax which is Rs
258 crore has been seen increasing by Rs 18.6 crore in 24.  The
EPS
of the company is 50.25 and is increasing by 38.8 in 24.
So
if we look at the results, the company's
quarter ended income has increased year on
year but due to very high expenses, the
company's profit is
seeing a very bad decline,
which may impact its shares
tomorrow because the
profit is down in quarter 100, even though the
company's revenue profit
increased in financial year 100, but the decline in quarter 100 may have a
huge impact year on year.
It does an
insurance business and that is why guys
see what happens in the insurance business,
like most of the insurance companies do many types of
insurance, be it vehicle insurance
or health insurance, it does many
types of business, so
what happens in vehicle insurance etc.,
it is in great demand during the festive season,
see there is a
lot of demand for vehicles during the festive season etc.
but in this season which is going on right now,
guys, in this fourth quarter season which
came, no special demand was seen
in vehicles etc. and
due to this the revenue profit of the company has also been
greatly impacted.  So now let's see
how he performs tomorrow.  If
we talk about the share, it closed at ₹1832.
Gave a profit of 6.6% today.  Because there was a
good rise in the market today.  A
positive breakout of around 2.1% was seen in the market today.  A
gap up was seen.
Due to which its shares rose.
Plus its results were also to be announced today.   There has been a
surge in this.  There is a profit of 2.4% in five days.
1 month profit is 6%.
For now guys you can wait and watch.
And see how it performs tomorrow.
Take decisions accordingly.  See you
in the next video, bye.